Finding Aid for the David P. Gamble papers LSC.1997
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Mandinka research materials, 1940-2006
  - Keneba: working groups, 1950-1951 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Keneba: notes on food, 1950-1952 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Keneba: census analysis, infant mortality, activities, 1950-1952 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Keneba and Kiang: Miscellaneous, circa 1963-1966 (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Keneba: 1970 visit (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Photocopy, Socioeconomic Impact of Tourism, 1978 (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - Mali, Pakoa, from Schaeffer, 1980s (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Extracts from books, classified by topic, circa 2000 (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript, Gambian Studies 49 (Mandinka agriculture), 2006 (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - Notes on early sources: general (1 of 3), 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Notes on early sources: general (2 of 3), 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Notes on early sources: general (3 of 3), 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Notes on early sources: economic aspect, 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Notes on early sources: arts and crafts, 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Notes on early sources: ceremonies, 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Notes on early sources: "Islam and paganism" (1 of 2), 1950s (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Notes on early sources: "Islam and paganism" (2 of 2), 1950s (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Field notes, 1946-1951 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography (Mandinka and Malinke), working copy, circa 1966 (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Articles and photocopies (including Malinke items) (1 of 3), circa 1989 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Articles and photocopies (including Malinke items) (2 of 3), circa 1989 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Articles and photocopies (including Malinke items) (3 of 3), circa 1989 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Card index of Mandinka words from King and Rowlands, circa 1987 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Transcripts of Mandinka stories (1 of 2), circa 1988 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Transcripts of Mandinka stories (2 of 2), circa 1988 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Lists of words from old books, circa 1987 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Vocabulary lists, including French sources, circa 1987 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Typescript copy of MacBrair's Grammar of the Mandingo (1837), circa 1984 (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Typescript copy of Hopkinson's Dictionary 1911, circa 1987 (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Word lists from various sources (1 of 2), circa 1984 (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Word lists from various sources (2 of 2), circa 1984 (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Typescript copy of O'Halloran's dictionary of 1948, circa 1984 (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Word lists, circa 1984 (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - Copies of Kibaro (1 of 2), 1950-1956 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Copies of Kibaro (2 of 2), 1950-1956 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Stories, songs, proverbs, idioms, 1948-1955 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Typescript, intro and corrections to Dictionary, 1955 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Extracts from Monteil, Khassonke (1915), circa 1970 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript and correspondence regarding Medical Mandinka, 1954-1958 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Peace Corps Dictionary, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Peace Corps Grammar, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Fajara Children's Centre Phrasebook, circa 1995 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Photocopies, articles on Mandinka language, circa 1987 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Working notes (1 of 3), circa 1949-1993 (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Working notes (2 of 3), circa 1949-1993 (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Working notes (3 of 3), circa 1949-1993 (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Corrections to "Notes on Mandinka" and offprint of article, 1949-1950 (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - Mandinka Narratives from Kibaro, 1976 (Box 87)
  - Mandinka legends and folktales, may include "Brer rabbit", undated (Box 40)
  - Maps and diagrams (Kerewan), 1948-1957 (Box 88, Folder 3)
- Series 4: The Gambia research materials, 1920-2007
  This series is comprised of materials related to Gamble's general research on The Gambia. It includes field notes and data related to Gamble's broad sociological surveys of the country's regions, as well as summaries and transcripts of primary sources consulted, including local "native" court records and district reports. This series is also comprised of notes on local and regional histories, as well as preparatory materials for Gamble's (1999) scholarly edition of Richard Jobson's The Discovery of River Gambra 1623. Professional correspondence regarding work in The Gambia and materials assembled for Gamble's anthropological exhibitions at San Francisco State University's Treganza Museum are also featured. Since there is some overlap between Gamble's general work on The Gambia and his ethnicity-based studies, some of the items in this series may be relevant to Mandinka, Wolof, and Fula research as well.
  - Progress reports, letters to Professor [Daryll] Forde (First three tours of Gambia), 1946-1956 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Motor bike log, 1947-1958 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - 1979 sabbatical (U.K. and Gambia) (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of articles on President's Award and Duke of Edinburgh's Scheme, 1977-2000 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Birmingham Conference: papers, diaries, correspondence, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Manding Conference (London), 1972 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Article for Encyclopedia of Africa, South of the Sahara, 1998 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Guidelines for Collier's Encyclopedia, 1982 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Britannica entries (offprints) and typescript of "Early Man" by Gamble, 1959-1977 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Treganza: Original manuscript, Gambian Items in the Adan E. Treganza Anthropology Museum (booklet), 1977 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Treganza: unbound copy, Gambian Items in the Adan E. Treganza Anthropology Museum (booklet), 1977 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Treganza: inventory and correspondence regarding gifts to Treganza Museum, 1977-1979 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Treganza: text, map, and publicity for Treganza Museum exhibit, 1999 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Treganza: illustrations for Treganza Museum publications, 1977-1986 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Treganza: manuscript, "Memories of the Gambia" exhibit, 1986 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Treganza: Gambian Items in the Adan E. Treganza Anthropology Museum (booklet), 1977 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Treganza: museum exhibit, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Eastword Publication manuscript and correspondence, 1996 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Gambian Studies photos (ceremonials), 1947-1949 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of Clio bibliography, 1988-1991 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Clio bibliography, circa 1988 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Reviews and minor articles, 1953-1954, 1961, 1963 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - References to Gamble's photographs, undated (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - List of photographic collections in London libraries, circa 1979 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript of Bibliography of the Gambia, 1958 (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - Typescript of article on wrestling, circa 1976 (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - Material on "The Last Unicorn" myth, circa 1997 (Box 73, Folder 21)
  - Old copies Notes Africaines (1 of 2), 1946-1973 (Box 73, Folder 22)
  - Old copies Notes Africaines (2 of 2), 1946-1973 (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript, "Socio-Economic Survey", 1949 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript, "Socio-Economic Survey" (corrected copy), 1950 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, Economic Conditions in Two Mandinka Villages, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1959 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Peter Weil, 1967-1983 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Matthew Hill and Emil A. Magel, 1977 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Hassan Njie, 1976-1994 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Undated correspondence and lists of contacts/students (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Gambia trip (1984) diaries, notes, finances (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Gambia trip (1986-1987) diaries, notes and addresses (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Notes and diaries from sabbatical trip, 1979 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Visit diaries and material from Peter Weil, correspondence, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Travel diaries, 1963-1970 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Official visitors, circa 1970s (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript, Gambian Studies #45, 2004 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript, Gambian Studies #46, 2004 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, Gambian Studies #47, 2005 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript, Bibliography of the Gambia, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - From Peace Corps- PRIST, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Notes from C.D. [Daryll] Forde, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Manekunda and Basse (Mandinka): census, 1960-1971 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Old notes on Manekunda and Basse, 1952-1954 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Early trade (notes on 16th-19th c. sources), undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Land/land tenure (including court records) (1 of 2), 1940s-1950s (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Land/land tenure (including court records) (2 of 2), 1940s-1950s (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Reports on Jenyer (Mandinka village)/Field Working Party, 1949-1954 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Jenyer (Mandinka village): general and court cases (1 of 2), 1949-1950 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Jenyer (Mandinka village): general and court cases (2 of 2), 1949-1950 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - List of Native court records seen, circa 1954 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Jenyer (Mandinka Village) ceremonies, 1949-1950 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Local history: Kaabu, Bundu, Bambuk, Khasso (notes from 18th and 19th century sources), 1955-1989 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Local history: Upper River Division (1 of 2), circa 1940s-1950s (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Local history: Upper River Division (2 of 2), circa 1940s-1950s (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Local history: Central Division, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Articles and notes on McCarthy/Janjanbure Isalnd, circa 1980s (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Local history: McCarthy Island Division, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Local history: Wester Division, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Prehistory, stone circles, monuments, 1947-1972 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Fula/Wolof/Mandinka cross-translations, undated (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Rainfall, circa 1940s (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography, urbanization, 1966 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Minor ethnic groups (notes on early sources), 18th-20th century (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Memos regarding land and chieftainship, 1932-1948 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Infant mortality, 1946-1952 (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Housing survey, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Slaves/slavery (notes on 17th-20th c. sources), undated (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Political organization, circa 1955 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - General/cross references, circa 1960 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Trade, agriculture, cattle (1 of 2), circa 1951 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Trade, agriculture, cattle (2 of 2), circa 1951 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Food, circa 1974 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Notes, manuscript, Bibliography of the Gambia, circa 1985 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Stanford/Berkeley conference paper, 1984-1985 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Photocopies of courses (18th-20th c.) (1 of 2), undated (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Photocopies of courses (18th-20th c.) (2 of 2), undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Index cards: People and historical characters (1 of 2), undated (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Index cards: People and historical characters (2 of 2), undated (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Old notes, arts and craft, circa 1996 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Index to Our Grandmother's Drums by Mark Hudson, circa 1990 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - The Chono, circa 1973 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Ocean traffic, river vessels, navigation, circa 1988 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Dates, undated (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - People, 1946-circa 1985 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Trees, food plants, circa 2001 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - General including old forts, undated (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - "Tribal names", undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Economics, 1940s-1950s (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Census of school children in Bathurst high schools, 1946 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Native courts and political organizations, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes: changes in cult groups, 1975 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Notes on law (regarding Oxford file), circa 1940s-1950s (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Kombo field notes (1 of 3), circa 1946-1956 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Kombo field notes (2 of 3), circa 1946-1956 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Kombo field notes (3 of 3), circa 1946-1956 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Kombo: notes on 19th-20th century sources, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1963-1986 (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Transcription, speech by Kukoi Samba Sanyaug, undated (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript, Gambian Studies 51 (Kombo Districts), 2006 (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Jobson book project: photocopy of G.Roure book, 1956 (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Jobson book project: photocopy A.R. Dupuy book, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Jobson book project: earlier edition of Golden Trade, 1968 (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Jobson book project: photocopies, Jobson-related, circa 1999 (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Jobson book project: photocopies from various books, circa 1990s (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Jobson book project: photocopy Teixeira da Mota book, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Jobson book project: journeys by river, circa 1990s (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Jobson book project: River Gambia and its parts, circa 1990s (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Jobson book project: various correspondence, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Jobson book project: correspondence with P.E.H. Hair, 1994-1997 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Jobson book project: correspondence with Public Record Office/British Library, 1996-1997 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Jobson book project: maps for text, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Jobson book project: diagrams and old photos, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Jobson book project: illustrations for text, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Jobson book project: photographs, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Jobson book project: notes and correspondence, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Jobson book project: place names, notes, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Jobson book project: photocopy of Jobson's petition, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Jobson book project: photocopy 1932 edition of The Golden Trade, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Jobson book project: photocopy Purchas' Voyages, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Jobson book project: typos, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Jobson book project: George Thompson and Jobson in Gambian histories, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Jobson book project: revised text, typescript, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Jobson book project: miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - Gambia tourism poster, undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Gambia district reports, undated (Box 47)
  - General: photocopies of Journal of Royal Anthropological Institute, 1960-1964 (Box 89, Folder 7)
- Series 5: Senegambian music research materials, 1975-2004
  This series is comprised of materials related to Gamble's research into Gambian, Senegalese, and Malian music. Gamble pursued this study on behalf of a colleague, Susan Carpendale, who was interested in exploring the connections between African and African-American music. The series includes annotated photocopies of secondary sources, original notes on sound recordings and written sources, and related correspondence. The "griot" (praise singing) traditions of Sudanic West Africa are emphasized.
  - For Susan Carpendale, circa 1993 (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Baaba Maal, circa 1995 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - Musical instruments, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - Material from internet, correspondence, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - Mark and Susan Pevar: notes on recordings and correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - Barbara Hoffman thesis, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Griots (1 of 3), circa 2002 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Griots (2 of 3), circa 2002 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Griots (3 of 3), circa 2002 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Mali (1 of 2), circa 1993 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Mali (2 of 2), circa 1993 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Tukulor Weavers' songs, circa 1990 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Pekaan, epic song of the Subalbe (Senegal), 1978-1982 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Fuuta Tooro (Fulbe/Fulani), 1975-1985 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Samba Gelajjo Jeegi, 1990s (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Mythical poems of herders (photocopy), 1986 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Africanisms/"survivals" (photocopies), 1990s (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Africa general (photocopies), 1990s (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - "Working notes: music on records", 1990s (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - "Creole" music (photocopies), 1990s (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Folklore: Black American, 1990s (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - African diaspora, 2000-2004 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous articles, circa 1993 (Box 81, Folder 5)
- Series 6: Photography, 1920-2007
  This series is divided into two subseries: one comprised of original photographic prints and negatives generated during Gamble's work in Senegambia and Sierra Leone, and one consisting of photographs clipped from newspapers and periodicals. Gamble's research photography documents daily activities, material culture, dress and hair, musical instruments, land use and agricultural techniques, and housing and architecture among Wolof, Mandinka, Fula, and Jola peoples. Biographical photos and mounted photos used in exhibits at San Francisco State College are also included. The second subseries contains news clippings relevant to Gamble's research.
  The first subseries is arranged chronologically. The second subseries has not been processed.
  - Subseries 6.1: Photo Prints and Negatives, 1920-2000
    - Misc. DPG Lifetime Photos, 1920-2004 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Photography Research, 1920-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Black and White Photos of early Gambia Documentation, 1940's (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Mandinka Ethnic Group in South Bank, Black and White and Negatives, 1940-1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Documentation of Kerewan, Gambia, Black and White Photos and negatives (1 of 2), 1940s and 1950s (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Documentation of Kerewan, Gambia, Black and White Photos and negatives (2 of 2), 1940s and 1950s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Travelling and Transport in the Gambia, BW photos and negatives, 1940s- 1950s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Documentation of Mandinka Ethnic Group BW Photos and Negatives, 1940s- 1950s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Wolof Ethnic Group BW Photos and Negatives (1 of 2), 1940s- 1950s (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Wolof Ethnic Group BW Photos and Negatives (2 of 2), 1940s- 1950s (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Housing in Kebeba, Gambia, 1946-1953 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Documentation of Musical Instruments, 1946-1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - River Craft Canoes, 1946-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lists of Photos contained in bibliographies, 1946-1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Gambia Research and Documentation-Black and White Photos, 1946-1979 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Blacksmith Documentation in Kaiaf, Gambia, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Jola Ethnic Group Housing and Agriculture Black and White Photos, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Groundnut Farming in Keneba, Gambia, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Agriculture Documentation, 1947-1979 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Rice Farming, 1947-1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Pictures of Jola Ethnic Group, 1947-1963 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - SFSU Exhibition Maps and Photo Explanations, 1947-1985 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Gamble Exhibition SFSU Cardboard Photos (1 of 3), 1947-1985 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Gamble Exhibition Cardboard Photos (2 of 3), 1947-1985 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Gamble Exhibition Cardboard Photos (3 of 3), 1947-1985 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Gamble Exhibition SFSU Cardboard Prints (1 of 4), 1947-1985 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Gamble Exhibition Cardboard Photos (2 of 4), 1947-1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Gamble Exhibition Cardboard Photos (3 of 4), 1947-1985 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Gamble Exhibition Cardboard Photos (4 of 4), 1947-1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Basketry Photography, 1947-1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Millet Farming in Kerewan, Gambia, 1948-1953 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Army Worm Effects in Gambia, 1948-1950 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Scenery in Kerewan, Gambia, Black and White Photos, 1948-1953 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - DPG and his motorcycle, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Rice Farming in Gambia B/W Photos and negatives, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Black and White Millet Farming Photos and negatives, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Mandinka Ethnic Group in Keneba, Gambia BW and negatives, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Negatives of Gambia Maps, 1950-1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Groundnut Farming in Gambia, BW photos and negatives, 1950s (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Documentation of Jola Ethnic Group, BW Photos and negatives, 1950s (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Documentation of the Gambia, Black and White and negatives, 1950s (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fula/Fulbe Ethnic Group BW Photos and negatives (1 of 2), 1950s (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Fula/Fulbe Ethnic Group BW Photos and negatives (2 of 2), 1950s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Photo Research and descriptions by DPG, 1950-1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Photos taken in Keneba, Gambia, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Negatives of DPG on motorcycle, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Agriculture in Keneba, Gambia, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Serahuli Ethnic Group, Black and White Negatives, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Photos of Fula Ethnic Group, 1953-1978 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - BW photo of Fula circumcision ceremony drummers, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Mandinka Ethnic Group Costumes, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Wolof Jewelry, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Sierra Leone Visit Documentation, 1960s and 1970s (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Photos taken in Sambakunda, Gambia, 1963-1972 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Farm Work for Women in Gambia, 1963-1972 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Photos of Wolof Ethnic Group, 1963-1987 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Mandinka Women, 1963-1972 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Color Prints of Gambian Daily Life Documentation, 1963-1986 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Photos of Misc Arts and Crafts in Gambia, 1965-1978 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Photos of Banjul,Gambia (small), 1965-1984 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Gambian Postcard Lists, 1966-1974 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Display Materials "The Gambia and America", 1966-1979 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Wolof Tools, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Gamble Exhibition Photo Labels (1 of 2), 1970-1980 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Gamble Exhibition Photo Labels (2 of 2), 1960-1970 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "Roots" and Alex Haley, 1972-1988 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Kumpo" Masquerade in Gambia, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Photos taken by Linda Salmon, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Negatives of "Memories of Gambia" Exhibit, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Upper River Gambian Documentation, 1974-1979 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Linda Salmon Portraits, 1974-2000 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Photos taken at Bakau Beach, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding Basket Photography, 1979-2005 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Gambia Tourism Poster, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Gamble's Gambia" Photo Exhibit Ephemera and Correspondence, 1980-2000 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Photos of Banjul, Gambia (large), 1986 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Photos Taken by Marc Pevar, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Memories of Gambia" Exhibit Slides, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Memories of Gambia" Exhibit Color Photos, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Images from "Senegal Behind Glass" Book, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Summary of Photographs from SFSU Exhibition, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 6.2: Photo clippings, undated
    - Picture files: news photo clippings (1 of 4), undated (Box 10)
    - Picture files: news photo clippings (2 of 4), undated (Box 11)